animalpetitions.org 2018-10-01

# Privacy Policy | Animal Petitions

We (“the Company”, “we”, “ForceChange”, “Animal Petitions”, “Play4Paws”, “Limited Liability Company”, or “us”) are a limited liability company and have established this privacy policy to explain to you how your information on ForceChange or Animal Petitions is protected, collected and used, which may be updated by us from time to time.

Protecting your privacy

The Company maintains the right to send you information via the postal mail services of your jurisdiction if such mailing is permissible pursuant to the laws of your jurisdiction. If you do not wish to receive information via the postal mail services, please contact us at https://animalpetitions.org/contact.

Your Personal Information (defined below) is not shared with any third parties without your consent except as noted below.

We do utilize tracking devices (“cookies”, “web beacons,” single-pixel gifs, etc.).

Cookies are small files that store information about your account, web browser, computer, mobile phone, or other device. Most companies on the web use cookies to enable special features or to provide you with a better, faster, or safer experience.

We use cookies to make ForceChange or Animal Petitions better and easier to use; to provide you with a more personalized experience; and to protect you, others, and ForceChange or Animal Petitions from malicious activity. For example, we use cookies to store your login ID (but never your password) so that it’s easier for you to log in when you return to the site. We also use cookies to confirm that you’re logged in to ForceChange or Animal Petitions.

We do not use cookies to create a profile of your browsing behavior on third-party sites, although we may use anonymous or aggregate data to track overall usage of ForceChange or Animal Petitions.

You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases, this may impact your ability to use ForceChange or Animal Petitions.

To remove yourself from a ForceChange or Animal Petitions email list, simply click “unsubscribe” at the bottom of the email. Notwithstanding the foregoing the Company maintains the right at all times to contact its members for business related purposes (some examples include, but are not limited to: (i) if a user requests a new password, (ii) if the Company chooses to alert its users about a site-related issue, or (iii) in response to an action taken by you using the Company’s products and/or services, such as signing a petition or updating your profile).

If you create a profile on the site, it will be visible to the public, anyone can view it and your profile may be indexed by internet search engines.

If you sign a petition or leave a comment on the site, your name and/or comment will be visible to the public, anyone can view it and your profile may be indexed by internet search engines.

If you sign a petition, a profile will be created for you on the site and that profile will be visible to the public, anyone can view it and your profile may be indexed by internet search engines.

We allow third-­-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our web site. These companies may utilize cookies, pixels or other technologies to collect and use both personally identifiable information (e.g., your name, phone number, physical or electronic address) and non-­- personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-­-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the websites of the Digital Advertising Alliance at www.aboutads.info or Networking Advertising Initiative at www.networkadvertising.org/choices.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Company who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. You may request a list of all of the third parties with whom we share your PII by sending an email via https://animalpetitions.org/contact and place “California Third Party Disclosure” in the subject line. Please allow up to thirty days for a response.

We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services. No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp. 

Additionally, emails we send may contain a bit of code known as a “web beacon.” This code allows us to understand the time and date of when a user has opened an email and when he/she has utilized a link within the email to visit a website. Our web beacons do not collect personally identifiable information. Users wishing to disable our web beacons should do so by turning images “off” in their email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see your email client for more information.” 

Your ForceChange or Animal Petitions account is password-protected. It is your obligation to safeguard your password. To update your password, login to your account, click on “Edit My Profile” and then change your password.

The Company does not knowingly collect information from individuals under the age of 13. If we become informed that a posting has been made by a person under the age of 13, we will remove all materials posted by such individual and will delete the account used by such person to access our website.

Postings and widgets on our website may include content and links from or to third party websites, and such websites will have different privacy policies than those set forth herein. We disclaim all responsibility for compliance with the privacy policies of those third party websites, and strongly urge all users to review such privacy policies.

Data we collect and store

As part of the registration and/or petition signing process, we may collect your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number and other contact information (your “Personal Information”) which will be stored in our database. We may additionally track data (including data which has been marked by the user as “Deleted”) relating to your behavior on the website (your “Campaign Activity Information”). Please do not post any personal information in any public forum of ForceChange or Animal Petitions which you expect to remain private, including, but not limited to, any Personal Information and/or Campaign Activity Information. We also reserve the right to collect any data about you which is publicly available; this data may be obtained by us or by a 3rd party engaged by us to collect such information.

We do NOT collect sensitive information from our users (including, but not limited, to personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual); however, a visitor to the website may be able to ascertain such sensitive information by the data which you choose to display on the Company’s website(s).

We make good faith efforts to store all collected data in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, although we cannot guarantee complete security.

Our web logs and newsletter service collect standard web log entries for each page served, including your IP address, page URL, and timestamp. Web logs help us to diagnose problems with our server, to administer the Company’s website, and to otherwise provide our services to you.

How we may use your data

We may share your Personal Information with the following third parties:

Affiliated third parties (for example, our programmers and database administrators) for the sole purpose of helping us do our work. These groups do not share your Personal Information or use it for any purpose other than as instructed by us.

If you sign a petition, please be advised that your Personal Information may be delivered to the intended recipient of such campaign and/or the creator of such campaign either electronically or in writing; the Company is not responsible for monitoring or attempting to verify the intended recipients of any campaign and/or the creator of any campaign and disclaims all liability regarding the accuracy of the intended recipient(s) of all campaigns and/or creator(s) of all campaigns. Please note further that by signing a petition, you are also consenting to the disclosure of your name on the landing page for such petition, indicating that you have signed such petition; this information will be visible to any visitor of our website, including search engines and other organizations which provide archival internet activities. Once a signature is entered on a petition, we cannot remove it.

If you would like to receive direct communication from the organizations you support, you may choose to have us pass your Personal Information to such organizations; please note that whenever you choose to have us pass such Personal Information to an organization, we will additionally inform the organization of the source campaign where you made this election. Please also be advised that the default settings for many of our campaigns assume that you wish to receive communications from the organizations you support; if you do not wish to receive such communications, please uncheck the box “Keep me updated by [name of organization]” (or other language of a similar nature) before signing such campaign. If you choose to receive direct communications from the organizations you support, please be advised that: (i) ForceChange or Animal Petitions has no control over the content, frequency and/or any other aspect of such communications; and (ii) it is fairly common practice for organizations to rent or trade the names and addresses of their donors with other organizations. Accordingly, we strongly urge you to review the terms of service, privacy policies and/or other like policies of any organization prior to consenting to our transmission of your Personal Information to such organization. Please note if you sign a petition hosted by a third party, for example without limitation, ThePetitionSite, we strongly encourage you to review the third party’s privacy policy and terms and conditions.

We sometimes partner with other organizations and may share your Personal Information with third parties that provide products and services that we think you may be interested in. Although our treatment of your Personal Information is governed by this Privacy Policy, the business partner or third party’s treatment of your Personal Information will be governed by the business partner or third party’s privacy policy.

In addition, we may utilize your Campaign Activity Information for internal purposes to help us personalize the experience for each user and to operate, maintain and improve the features and functionality of our website. Please note that if you sign a petition, third parties will have access to such information as your name.

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary set forth herein, the Company: (1) may disclose information about its users if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; and (2) may also disclose information about its users to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) enforce our Terms of Service; (b) respond to claims that any posting or other content violates the rights of third-parties; (c) or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of the Company, its users or the general public.

In the event that the Company is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.

Archiving and display of ForceChange or Animal Petitions postings by search engines and other sites

Search engines and other websites unaffiliated with the Company may archive or otherwise make available information publicly displayed on our website, including without limitation your name.

International Users

By visiting our web site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that due to the international dimension of ForceChange or Animal Petitions, we may use the data collected in the course of our relationship for the purposes identified in this policy or in our other communications with you, including the transmission of information outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, please understand that such data may be stored on servers located in the United States. By providing us with your data, you consent to the transfer of such data.

Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

All disputes resultant from this Privacy Policy shall be adjudicated pursuant to the mechanisms set forth in our Terms of Service.

This Privacy Policy is compliant with: (i) the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor Framework, and (ii) the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework.

If you need any assistance or would like to provide feedback on this document, please contact us (http://animalpetitions.org/contact).
